James F. Carr Papers
James F. Carr Papers
1876-1971
Carr, James F.
8 linear ft.
Papers of the American bookseller, brother of Raymond Carr. Collection pertains largely to theater investments of Carr's brother, Raymond, and includes correspondence, photographs of film and stage actors, and various printed theatrical memorabilia such as clippings, playbills, programs, and posters.
148888
Biographical History
James F. Carr was an American bookseller. His brother, Raymond Carr, was a theatre investor.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The James F. Carr Papers consist of correspondence, memorabilia, photographs, playbills, printed Material, and published material. The bulk of the collection is theatre-oriented.
Correspondence pertains mainly to theatre investments made by Raymond Carr, James' brother. This series also contains a letter to S.R. Koehler, dated June 2, 1883 from James M. Ives, partner in Currier and Ives.
Photographs contains many studio photos of stage and film personalities as well as unidentified others. A partial list of photographs in the James F. Carr Papers includes Jean Arthur, Lionel Barrymore, Sarah Bernhardt, Omar Bradley, Lon Chaney, Henry Clay, Frank Daniels, Jefferson Davis, Douglas Fairbanks, Della Fox, Japan, Buster Keaton, Jeanette MacDonald, Adolphe Menjou, Robert Montgomery, Edmund Muskie, Julia Neilson, Olga Nethersole, New York Central and Lackawanna Railroad, New Zealand, Richard Nixon, Rubens Peale (signed), Mary Pickford, Joseph Schildkraut, Sitting Bull, E. H. Sothern, Harry Truman, Fay Wray. Some are signed, some are not; some are original photos, others are studio publicity pictures.
Playbills contains theatre playbills for various productions, the bulk of which were in the late 1960's. Printed material contains limited partnership agreements and offering circulars for many of Raymond Carr's investments. Published material includes many opera and souvenir programs as well as newspaper clippings pertaining to plays Raymond Carr supported financially.
Arrangement of the Collection
All series are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
has numerous collections relating to radio, television and film personalities. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Popular culture; Radio, television, film; Carr, James F.; Carr, Raymond.; Actors -- Portraits.; Playbills -- Collections.; Theater -- Finance.; Theater -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Playbills.; Programs (documents)
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence
  - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Forum, 1962-1971 (Box 1)
  - A Joyful Noise, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - An Evening with Elaine Ma and Mike Nichols, 1960-1963 (Box 1)
  - Auntie Mame / Mame, 1960-1970 (Box 1)
  - Cabaret, 1960-1970 (Box 1)
  - Cabaret, 1966-1971 (Box 1)
  - Company, 1969-1971 (Box 1)
  - Daphine in Cottage D, 1966 (Box 1)
  - Der Rosenkavalier, 1963-1969 (Box 1)
  - Desk Set, 1961-1971 (Box 1)
  - The Education of Hyman Kaplan, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Entertaining Mr. Sloane, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Fetch Me A Fig Leaf, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Fiddler on the Roof (2 folders), 1964-1971 (Box 1)
  - Fiorello!, 1960-1971 (Box 1)
  - Flora, the Red Menace, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Follies, 1970-1971 (Box 1)
  - The of Poppies, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Hamlet, 1963-1971 (Box 1)
  - Hay Fever, 1970 (Box 1)
  - Hotel Passionato, 1965 (Box 1)
  - How to Succeed in Business Without Really Trying, 1961-1965 (Box 1)
  - S.R. Koehler, 1876-1890 (Box 1)
  - Love Happy, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous, 1958-1971; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - The Most Happy Fella, 1958-1971 (Box 1)
  - Personal, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Peterpat, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Petroleum Investment Offerings, 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Poor Bitos, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Prettybelle, 1971 (Box 1)
  - She Loves Me, 1962-1966 (Box 1)
  - Simon Doesn't Live Here Anymore, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Slaves, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
  - Tenderloin, 1960-1963 (Box 2)
  - Walking Happy, 1966-1967 (Box 2)
  - West Side Story, 1960-1971 (Box 2)
  - Zorba Joint Venture, 1969-1971 (Box 2)
- Memorabilia
  - Etching block (Box 2)
  - Posters (Oversize 1)
  - Ticket stubs, 1958-1971 (Box 2)
  - Washington Briefing for Young Americans, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
- Photographs
  - Miscellaneous, 11 folders (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 19 folders (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous (Oversize 2)
- Playbills
  - After the Rain, 1967 (Box 4)
  - A Funny Thing Happened on the Way to the Forum, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Agatha Sue I love you, 1966 (Box 4)
  - A Joyful Noise, 1966 (Box 4)
  - All The Way Home, 1960 (Box 4)
  - Alvin Ailey American Dance Theater, 1971 (Box 4)
  - A Minor Adjustment, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Anne of the Thousand Days, 1948 (Box 4)
  - The Apple Tree, 1966 (Box 4)
  - A Time for Singing, 1966 (Box 4)
  - The Auctioneer, 1914 (Box 4)
  - 3 Bags Full, 1966 (Box 4)
  - The Ballad of the Sand Cafe, 1963-1964 (Box 4)
  - Baker Street, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Bascom Barlow, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Becket, 1961 (Box 4)
  - The Best Laid Plans, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Black Comedy, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Cabaret, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Cactus Flower, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - The Chalk Garden, 1955 (Box 4)
  - Come Live With Me, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Daphine in Cottage D, 1967 (Box 4)
  - The Diary of Anne Frank, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Don't Drink the Water, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Dr. Cook's Garden, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Fallen Angels, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Fiorello!, 1959 (Box 4)
  - First One Asleep, Whistle, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Flora, the Red Menace, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Follies, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Fragments, 1964 (Box 4)
  - The Glass Menagerie, 1965 (Box 4)
  - The Great Indoors, 1966 (Box 4)
  - The Great Sebastians, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Hallelujah, Baby!, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Hamlet, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Happily Ever After, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Hello, Dolly!, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Henry, Sweet Henry, 1967 (Box 4)
  - The Highest Tree, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Home, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Hostile Witness, 1966 (Box 4)
  - How's the World Treating You?, 1966 (Box 4)
  - I Do ! I Do !, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Inadmissible Evidence, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Inherit the Wind, 1955-1957 (Box 4)
  - Ivanov, 1966 (Box 4)
  - I Was Dancing, 1964 (Box 4)
  - Johnny No-Trump, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Jolly's Progress, 1959 (Box 4)
  - La Grosse Valise, 1965 (Box 4)
  - The Lion in Winter, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Little Me, 1962 (Box 4)
  - Lovely Ladies, Kind Gentlemen, 1970 (Box 4)
  - Major Barbara, 1956 (Box 4)
  - Malcolm, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Mame, 1966 (Box 4)
  - The Matchmaker, 1955 (Box 4)
  - The Miracle Worker, 1959 (Box 4)
  - More Stately Mansions, 1967 (Box 4)
  - My Sweet Charlie, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Nathan Weinstein, Mystic, Connecticut, 1966 (Box 4)
  - New Girl in Town, 1957 (Box 4)
  - No, No, Nanette, 1971 (Box 4)
  - The Odd Couple, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Peterpat, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Philadelphia, Here I Come!, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Pousse-Cafe, 1966 (Box 4)
  - The Promise, 1967 (Box 4)
  - 1776, 1971 (Box 4)
  - Sherry!, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Shinbone Alley, 1957 (Box 4)
  - Silent Night, Lonely Night, 1959 (Box 4)
  - Slapstick Tragedy, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Song of the Grasshopper, 1967 (Box 4)
  - The Star-Spangled Girl, 1966 (Box 4)
  - Strange Interlude, 1963 (Box 4)
  - Superman, 1966 (Box 4)
  - That Summer-That Fall, 1967 (Box 4)
  - There's A Girl in My Soup, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Tiger at the Gates, 1956 (Box 4)
  - The Trial of Lee Harvey Oswald, 1967 (Box 4)
  - The Unknown Soldier and His Wife, 1967 (Box 4)
  - Utbu, 1966 (Box 4)
  - The Vamp, 1955 (Box 5)
  - Wait a Minim!, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Wait Until Dark, 1966 (Box 5)
  - The Waltz of the Toreadors, 1967 (Box 5)
  - The Wayward Stork, 1966 (Box 5)
  - We Have Always Lived in the Castle, 1966 (Box 5)
  - "What Did We Do Wrong?", 1967 (Box 5)
  - Where's Daddy?, 1966 (Box 5)
  - Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf, 1962-1964; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - You Know I Can't Hear You When the Water's Running, 1967 (Box 5)
- Printed material
  - Banquet Invitation, 1911 (Box 5)
  - Financial Statements, 1959-1970 (Box 5)
  - Invitation to Third Anniversary Celebration of Hair, 1971 (Box 5)
  - Limited Partnership Agreements, 1957-1971; 4 folders (Box 5)
  - The Living Theatre, 1951-1963 (Box 5)
  - Miscellaneous, 1923 (Box 5)
  - Offering Circulars, 1957-1971 (Box 5)
- Scripts
  - The Fume of Poppies (Box 6)
  - Making Love Legal, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Slaves, 1968 (Box 6)
- Published material
  - Carnegie Hall Program, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Evergreen Program for The Deer Park, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Handbills, 1963-1971 (Box 6)
  - Magazine clippings, 1959-1971; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Magazines
    - Cue, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Equity, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Life (Oversize 3)
    - Ken Murray's Hollywood (Box 6)
    - Plays and Players, 1966-1967 (Box 6)
    - Saturday Review, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Metropolitan Opera House Programs
    - Le Nozze di Figaro, 1956 (Box 6)
    - Lucia di Lammermoor, 1956 (Box 6)
    - Madama Butterfly, 1962 (Box 6)
    - The Royal Ballet, 1967 (Box 6)
  - Mohawk Airlines
    - Annual Reports, 1949-1966 (Box 6)
    - Information, 1964-1968 (Box 6)
    - Newsletter, The Air Chief, 1955-1967 (Box 6)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1961-1971
    - Miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous, 6 folders (Box 7)
    - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Pittsburgh Opera Program, La Sonnambula, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Programs, miscellaneous, 1902-1967 (Box 9)
  - Radio City Music Hall Programs, 1964 (Box 9)
  - Souvenir Programs
    - Actor's Equity Golden Anniversary Show, 1963 (Oversize 3)
    - Baker Street, 1965 (Oversize 3)
    - Balieff's Chauve - Souris of Moscow (Box 9)
    - Beyond the Fringe (Box 9)
    - The Consul (Box 9)
    - Katherine Cornell (Box 9)
    - Fiddler on the Roof (Box 9)
    - Hamlet (Box 9)
    - Hamlet, 1964 (Oversize 3)
    - Henry IV (Box 9)
    - How to Succeed in Business Without Really Trying (Oversize 3)
    - Macbeth (Box 9)
    - Mame (Box 9)
    - Pavlowa (Box 9)
    - The Pirate (Box 9)
    - Stop the World, I Want to Get Off (Box 9)
    - Sweet Charity, 1966 (Box 9)
    - There Shall Be No Night (Box 9)
    - A Time for Singing (Oversize 3)
    - Twelfth Night (Box 9)
    - West Side Story (Box 9)
  - Theatre Forecast, 1962-1963 (Box 9)
  - Theatre Round-Up, 1964-1965 (Box 9)